A Guide to the Executive Letter Books of the Virginia Office of the Governor, 1780-1906
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Executive Letter Books of the Virginia Office of the Governor, 1780-1906
The Library of Virginia
35358
47 volumes
Virginia. Office of the Governor
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Alternate Form of Material
Microfilm copy available (Miscellaneous Reels 2999-3015)
Biographical Information
X
Scope and Content
Executive letter books, 1780-1906, are comprised of copies of outgoing letters of Virginia Governors. Most volumes are indexed by recipient name.
Letter book, 1780 July-Sept 13, (Thomas Jefferson) is available as a negative photostat and a typewritten transcription. Original is at the British Museum. (Accession 13868).
Letter book, 1781 Aug 22 - Nov 29 (Thomas Nelson; David Jameson) also includes a handwritten transcript of the original.
Arrangement
These volumes are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Executive letter books, 1780-1906.
  - Executive letter book (Thomas Jefferson - Negative photostat and typewritten transcription), 1780 July-Sept 13. (Box 1)
  - Executive letter book (Thomas Jefferson), 1780 Dec 24 - 1781 Apr 27 (Miscellaneous Reel 2999). (Box 2)
  - Executive letter book (Thomas Jefferson; Thomas Nelson), 1781 Apr 26 - Aug 15 (Miscellaneous Reel 3000). (Box 3)
  - Executive letter book (Thomas Nelson; David Jameson), 1781 Aug 22 - Nov 29 (Miscellaneous Reel 3000). (Box 4)
  - Executive letter book (Benjamin Harrison), 1781 Dec 1 - 1782 Sept 30 (Miscellaneous Reel 3000). (Box 5)
  - Executive letter book (Benjamin Harrison), 1782 Oct 3 - Dec 28 (Miscellaneous Reel 3000). (Box 6)
  - Executive letter book (Benjamin Harrison and Edmund Randolph), 1783 Jan 1 - 1786 Nov 27 (Miscellaneous Reel 3001). (Box 7)
  - Executive letter book (Edmund Randolph and Beverly Randolph), 1786 Dec 1 - 1788 Dec 5 (Miscellaneous Reel 3001). (Box 8)
  - Executive letter book (Beverly Randolph and Henry Lee), 1788 Dec 6 - 1792 May 10 (Miscellaneous Reel 3002). (Box 9)
  - Executive letter book (Henry Lee), 1792 May 11 - 1794 Sept 24 (Miscellaneous Reel 3002). (Box 10)
  - Executive letter book (Henry Lee and James Monroe), 1794 Oct 4 - 1800 Oct 5 (Miscellaneous Reel 3003). (Box 11)
  - Executive letter book (James Monroe and John Page), 1800 Oct 5 - 1803 Oct 18 (Miscellaneous Reel 3004). (Box 12)
  - Executive letter book (John Page and William H. Cabell), 1803 Oct 24 - 1807 July 8 (Miscellaneous Reel 3005). (Box 13)
  - Executive letter book (William H. Cabell), 1807 July 8 - 1808 Mar 9 (Miscellaneous Reel 3006). (Box 14)
  - Executive letter book (William H. Cabell and John Tyler), 1808 Mar 9 - 1810 Jan 15 (Miscellaneous Reel 3007). (Box 15)
  - Executive letter book (John Tyler and George W. Smith), 1810 Jan 15 - 1811 Aug 24 (Miscellaneous Reel 3008). (Box 16)
  - Executive letter book (George W. Smith and James Barbour), 1811 Aug 24 - 1812 July 29 (Miscellaneous Reel 3009). (Box 17)
  - Executive letter book (James Barbour), 1812 July 29 - 1813 Dec 1 (Miscellaneous Reel 3010). (Box 18)